<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Weblog | Mike Chambers]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/blog/categories/weblog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-15T20:32:01-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mike Chambers]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[mikechambers.com Now Hosted at MediaTemple.net]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2007/10/29/weblog-now-hosted-at-mediatemplenet/"/>
    <updated>2007-10-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2007/10/29/weblog-now-hosted-at-mediatemplenet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just a quick note, but I have changed hosting providers for my weblog. The transition should be pretty seamless, and if you are reading this, then you are all set. It might take a day or two for the DNS to update.</p>

<p>The weblog is now being hosted by <a href="http://www.mediatemple.net">MediaTemple</a>. They were one of the partners of the <a href="http://onair.adobe.com">on air tour</a>, and hosted the website. They gave us excellent support, and thus when I started to look for a new host, they were the first people I contacted.</p>

<p>The transition should be pretty smooth, but if you run into any issues, just leave a comment on this post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Videos Do You Want to See at video.onflex.org]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2007/04/04/what-videos-do-you-want-to-see-at-videoonflexorg/"/>
    <updated>2007-04-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2007/04/04/what-videos-do-you-want-to-see-at-videoonflexorg</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, <a href="http://www.onflex.org">Ted Patrick</a> and I launched <a href="http://video.onflex.org">video.onflex.org</a> a little over 3 weeks ago, and we are already nearing our twentieth video on the site. If you haven&#8217;t checked it out yet, make sure to <a href="http://video.onflex.org">glance through some of the videos</a>.</p>

<p>Anyways, we are nearing the end of our backlog of videos, and it looks like I have some time this Thursday and Friday to create some more videos, so:</p>

<p><strong>What Flex and / or Apollo videos you want to see on video.onflex.org? What do you want us to show? Who do you want us to interview?</strong></p>

<p>Let us know by posting your thoughts in the comments.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mike Chambers&#8217; Weblog Has Moved]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2005/05/17/mike-chambers-weblog-has-moved/"/>
    <updated>2005-05-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2005/05/17/mike-chambers-weblog-has-moved</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As you have probably noticed, my weblog has moved from markme.com to weblogs.macromedia.com.</p>

<p>The new url is:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.mikechambers.com/mesh/">http://www.mikechambers.com/mesh/</a></p>

<p>Make sure to update your urls for the site and the <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/MikeChambers">rss</a> feeds.</p>

<p>Christian Cantrell&#8217;s weblog has also moved, and eventually all of the weblogs on markme.com will be transitioned over.</p>

<p>The biggest changes are that the site has a new look (although not necessarily good). I tweaked the default templates, so they don&#8217;t look so hot, but I am going to try to spiff it up some over the coming weeks.</p>

<p>The other big change is that we are using a new spam controll system, which should hopefully reduce or eliminate weblog spam.</p>

<p>Finally, we have tried to redirect everything from markme.com, but there are probably quite a few links and posts still broken. So, if you find any errors, you can just post them in the comments here.</p>

<p>Updated : April 23, 2007 to point to new domain.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Custom Quickcode Tags for MoveableType]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2005/05/17/custom-quickcode-tags-for-moveabletype/"/>
    <updated>2005-05-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2005/05/17/custom-quickcode-tags-for-moveabletype</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the new plugins we installed on the new weblog server is the <a href="http://mt-stuff.fanworks.net/plugin/quick_code_version_10.phtml">Quickcode plugin</a> for <a href="http://www.moveabletype.org">Moveabletype</a> This is a simple plugin that uses bracketed tags to make it easy to mark up posts.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Instead of typing:</p>

<p><code></code></p>

<pre>&lt;a href="mailto:mesh@macromedia.com"&gt;mesh@macromedia.com&lt;/a&gt;</pre>


<p>I can type:</p>

<pre>[email]mesh@macromedia.com[/email]</pre>


<p>The syntax is easy to use, which is the main reason I installed it.</p>

<p>Once I began using it, I realized it would be useful to create a number of other tags, so I opened up the plugin file (written in Perl) and hacked around until I got some new tags working. I wanted to post them here in case anyone else found them useful.</p>

<p>Here are the new tags:</p>

<pre>[mxna]TERM[/mxna] - Links the term for a search at the Macromedia XML News Aggregator (MXNA)

[google]TERM[/google] - Links the term for a search at Google

[wikipedia]TERM[/wikipedia] - Links the term for a search / link at wikipedia

[url2]TERM[/url2] - Links the included URL, with the URL as the link.</pre>


<p>Here are some examples:</p>

<p>This searches for [mxna]mesh[/mxna] at MXNA.<br/>
This searches for [google]Mike Chambers[/google] at Google.<br/>
This search for [wikipedia]Macromedia Flash[/wikipedia] at wikipedia.org.<br/>
This creates a link to my new weblog at [url2]<a href="http://weblogs.macromedia.com/mesh/">http://weblogs.macromedia.com/mesh/</a>[/url2]</p>

<p>To install these, [url=<a href="http://mt-stuff.fanworks.net/plugin/quick_code_version_10.phtml">http://mt-stuff.fanworks.net/plugin/quick_code_version_10.phtml</a>]download and install[/url] the quickcode.pl file. Open the file in a text editor, and search for the following lines inside of the maincode sub:</p>

<p><code></code></p>

<pre>$s =~ s![email](.*?)[/email]!&lt;a href="mailto:$1"&gt;$1&lt;/a&gt;!gis;</pre>


<p>Insert the following lines after the line above:</p>

<p><code></code></p>

<pre>$s =~ s![mxna](.*?)[/mxna]!&lt;a href="http://weblogs.macromedia.com/mxna/index.cfm?searchterms=$1"&gt;$1&lt;/a&gt;!gis;

$s =~ s![google](.*?)[/google]!&lt;a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=$1"&gt;$1&lt;/a&gt;!gis;

$s =~ s![wikipedia](.*?)[/wikipedia]!&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:Search?search=$1"&gt;$1&lt;/a&gt;!gis;

$s =~ s![url2](.*?)[/url2]!&lt;a href="$1"&gt;$1&lt;/a&gt;!gis;</pre>


<p>Save the file. Now when you make a post using Quickcode formatting, you can use the new tags.</p>

<p>If you can think of any useful tags to create, post them in the comments.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New MXNA Features / Contest Winners]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2005/05/05/new-mxna-features-contest-winners/"/>
    <updated>2005-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2005/05/05/new-mxna-features-contest-winners</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I mentioned yesterday, we have released an small update to <a href="http://weblogs.macromedia.com/mxna/">MXNA</a> (our Macromedia Community News Aggregator).</p>

<p>In addition to a bunch of tweaks and bugs fixes, there are some cool new features, including:</p>

<!--more-->


<ul>
<li><a href="http://weblogs.macromedia.com/mxna/FeedList.cfm">New Per-Feed Feed Reports / Summaries</a> (very cool)</li>
<li><a href="http://weblogs.macromedia.com/mxna/reports/mostPopularPostsAvg/index.cfm">New Last Day Most Popular Averages Report</a></li>
<li><a href="http://weblogs.macromedia.com/mxna/index.cfm?query=byMostPopularYear">Listing of most popular posts from last year</a></li>
<li><a href="http://weblogs.macromedia.com/mxna/index.cfm?query=byMostPopularAllTime">Listing of most popular posts of all time</a></li>
</ul>


<p>If you have a weblog aggregated by MXNA, then I think the new <a href="http://weblogs.macromedia.com/mxna/FeedList.cfm">feed specific report</a> is the coolest new feature. They allow you to view click stats for the last fifty posts made on a per feed basis. This makes it easy to see what types of posts were the most popular, what your average clicks are, and what the current trends are.</p>

<p>You can view a report for a specific feed by going to the <a href="http://weblogs.macromedia.com/mxna/FeedList.cfm">Weblogs listing page</a>, and clicking the Feed Report link for the feed you want to view.</p>

<p>Congrats to the winners of yesterdays quick contest, who noticed the new features:</p>

<ul>
<li>Nisse Bryngfors (Click Reports)</li>
<li>Galileo (Clicks Icon)</li>
<li>Ryan Guill</li>
</ul>


<p>Bonus points to Galileo, who won the most perceptive award by noticing that the clicks icon for each post had been slightly changed to include a fill color.</p>

<p>If you are one of the winners, send me an email (<a href="&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#108;&#116;&#111;&#58;&#x6d;&#x65;&#115;&#104;&#64;&#x6d;&#97;&#x63;&#114;&#111;&#x6d;&#101;&#100;&#105;&#x61;&#46;&#99;&#111;&#109;">&#109;&#101;&#x73;&#104;&#64;&#x6d;&#x61;&#99;&#114;&#111;&#109;&#101;&#x64;&#105;&#x61;&#46;&#99;&#111;&#109;</a>) with your mailing info, and Ill send out your Flash bags today.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
