<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: On AIR Tour | Mike Chambers]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/blog/categories/on-air-tour/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-15T20:32:01-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mike Chambers]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speaking in Europe on Flex and AIR (on AIR Tour)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2008/02/20/speaking-in-europe-on-flex-and-air-on-air-tour/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2008/02/20/speaking-in-europe-on-flex-and-air-on-air-tour</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I am guessing you have read by now, we just <a href="http://onair.adobe.com/blogs/tour/2008/02/19/on-air-tour-european-cities-and-dates/">announced</a> the <a href="http://onair.adobe.com/schedule/">cities and dates</a> for the European leg of the <a href="http://onair.adobe.com">on AIR Tour</a>. We will be traveling to 12 cities through out Europe (via train) and holding free one day developer events around Adobe AIR. Sessions cover both Flash and Flex, as well as JavaScript and HTML based development.</p>

<p><a href="http://onair.adobe.com"><img src="http://onair.adobe.com/images/branding.gif" alt="logo" border="0" /></a></p>

<p>I will be doing an intro session, showing how to build your first AIR application using Flex and Flex Builder. I will also be MCing the event, as well as playing a lot of guitar hero, and hanging out with other developers.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I am really excited about the tour. We realize after the first leg of the North American leg of the tour, that we wanted to bring the tour to Europe. The North American leg was a huge success, and we got to meet and chat with tons of developers (and see a lot of cool apps).</p>

<p>We have a pretty impressive line up of <a href="http://onair.adobe.com/tour/">speakers</a> and sessions for all of the events (with the exact lineup changing from <a href="http://onair.adobe.com/schedule/">city to city</a>). We start the day of with the basics, and then go over some of the new APIs that AIR offers, and then cover a bunch of demos, and example applications.</p>

<p>To be honest though, I am most excited about the tour because it is just flat out fun. I get to meet tons of new developers at the events, see new apps, hear new ideas. On the North American leg of the tour, we hung out with a lot of people after the events, and I made a lot of new friends, and I expect the same will happen in Europe. Even the travel is fun, as I get to hang out with some super talented developers, and work on apps (or just mess around). (I was in Europe on a speaking tour in the Fall, so Im hoping I get to meet up again with a lot of the people I met).</p>

<p>Oh yeah, and we have some cool schwag too&hellip; ;)</p>

<p>Anyways, we try to get a pretty good mix of developers at the events, with a target of around 50% Flash and Flex developers and 50% JavaScript / HTML developers (that includes PHP, Java, etc&hellip;). We really rely on word of mouth, so if you know someone doing web development, then make sure to let them know about the tour. Even if they are not interested in AIR, it is a good chance to hang out, and meet a lot of other web developers in the area. If you are planning on attending, make sure to blog the tour, and let people know.</p>

<p>You can find a complete list of dates and cities, as well and information on how to register on the <a href="http://onair.adobe.com">onair website</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slides From Deconstructing the Bus FlashForward Session]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2007/09/19/slides-from-deconstructing-the-bus-flashforward-session/"/>
    <updated>2007-09-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2007/09/19/slides-from-deconstructing-the-bus-flashforward-session</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finished up my presentation at FlashForward. It was titled <a href="http://www.flashforwardconference.com/sessions?sid=803">On the Road with Adobe AIR</a> and I took apart some of the AIR applications that we use on the bus to power the <a href="http://onair.adobe.com/api/">online APIs</a>.</p>

<p>I have <a href="http://onairbustour.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/projects/presentations/DeconstructingTheBus/">uploaded all of the slides and files</a> for the presentation to the bus tour&#8217;s subversion repository.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mikechambers/1408547308/" title="Photo Sharing"><img src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1327/1408547308_28978ddb28_m.jpg" width="187" height="240" alt="Online / Offline Data Syncing Flow" /></a></p>

<p>Here are the links from the session:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://onairbustour.googlecode.com/svn/trunk/projects/presentations/DeconstructingTheBus/">Slides and Files</a></li>
<li><a href="http://onair.adobe.com">Bus Tour Website</a></li>
<li><a href="http://onair.adobe.com/api/">Bus Tour APIs</a></li>
<li><a href="http://code.google.com/p/onairbustour/">Source Code for Apps</a></li>
<li><a href="http://onair.adobe.com/blogs/videos/2007/07/15/tour-of-on-air-bus-pre-tour/">Video Tour of Bus</a></li>
<li><a href="http://theflashblog.com/?p=272">Video Highlights of Leg 1 of Tour</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Post any questions in the comments.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hitting the Road Again]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2007/09/18/hitting-the-road-again/"/>
    <updated>2007-09-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2007/09/18/hitting-the-road-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, now that I have finally recovered from leg two of the <a href="http://onair.adobe.com">on AIR Bus tour</a>, it is time to hit the road again for a marathon tour of the East coast and Midwest.</p>

<p>First up is <a href="http://www.flashforwardconference.com">FlashForward</a> in Boston this week. I am really excited about this conference, as for various reasons, I havent been to the past couple of Flash Forwards. In addition to getting to see and hang out with all of my friends, I am presenting a session titled <a href="http://www.flashforwardconference.com/sessions?sid=803">On the Road with Adobe AIR</a>, in which I will be deconstructing some of the AIR applications that we use to power the bus tour.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>There are a number of other AIR related sessions, including:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.flashforwardconference.com/sessions?sid=801">Integrating with Adobe Media Player</a> Jen Taylor</li>
<li><a href="http://www.flashforwardconference.com/sessions?sid=798">AIR Outside the Box</a> Keith Peters</li>
<li><a href="http://www.flashforwardconference.com/sessions?sid=810">AIR, Finetune Desktop, and the Circle of Engagement</a> Tony MacDonald</li>
</ul>


<p>Of course, you can imagine that there might also be a mention or two about Adobe AIR during <a href="http://www.flashforwardconference.com/sessions?sid=786">Kevin Lynch&#8217;s Keynote</a>.</p>

<p>The on AIR tour bus will actually be picking us up in Boston on Friday night to take us down to New York city to start the <a href="http://onair.adobe.com">tour</a>. We will be hitting <a href="http://onair.adobe.com/schedule/cities/newyork.php">New York City</a>, <a href="http://onair.adobe.com/schedule/cities/newyork.php">Toronto</a>, <a href="http://onair.adobe.com/schedule/cities/minneapolis.php">Minneapolis</a>, and <a href="http://onair.adobe.com/schedule/cities/chicago.php">Chicago</a> for AIR Camp events.</p>

<p>I am really excited about the New York trip, because Halo 3 comes out on Midnight, Monday night. We will be waiting in line at the Best Buy on 5th Avenue, and then will be getting on the bus afterwards to head to Toronto (I don&#8217;t plan to sleep much that night).</p>

<p>Finally, the bus tour will end up in Chicago and the <a href="http://www.adobe.com/events/max/">Adobe MAX conference</a>. The bus will actually be parked in the venue, and we will open it up during one of the parties. I haven&#8217;t posted about it much this summer, but MAX is going to rock. Ted Patrick has been leading the charge on it, and I can honestly say that this is by far the most excited I have ever been about MAX.</p>

<p>Anyways, if you are at any of the events over the next couple of weeks, make sure to say hi.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Offline Most of This Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2007/08/27/offline-most-of-this-week/"/>
    <updated>2007-08-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2007/08/27/offline-most-of-this-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just a quick fyi, but I will be offline most of the week recuperating from the last two weeks on the road with the <a href="http://onair.adobe.com">on AIR Bus tour</a> (<a href="http://onair.adobe.com/schedule/">leg 3 starts up in a couple of weeks</a>).</p>

<p>If you send me an email, it might take me a little while to respond.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Speaking in Philadelphia Tonight]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2007/08/22/speaking-in-philadelphia-tonight/"/>
    <updated>2007-08-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.mikechambers.com/blog/2007/08/22/speaking-in-philadelphia-tonight</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just a quick reminder, but the <a href="onair.adobe.com/schedule/cities/philadelphia.php">on AIR Bus</a> has rolled into <a href="onair.adobe.com/schedule/cities/philadelphia.php">Philadelphia</a> today, and we will be holding an AIR Camp event tonight. I will be speaking, along with the rest of the the <a href="http://onair.adobe.com/bus/">bus crew</a>.</p>

<p>We will have plenty of food, beer, code, schwag and other goodness, so <a href="onair.adobe.com/schedule/cities/philadelphia.php">if you are in Philly, make sure to stop by</a>.</p>

<p>Btw, where is the best place to get a cheesesteak in Philly? We just hit <a href="http://www.patskingofsteaks.com/">Pat&#8217;s</a>, where should we go after the event?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
