<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Flash Resource Manager | Mike Chambers]]></title>
  <link href="http://mikechambers.github.io/blog/categories/flash-resource-manager/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mikechambers.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-15T16:15:00-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mikechambers.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mike Chambers]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flash Resource Manager and Flash 8]]></title>
    <link href="http://mikechambers.github.io/2005/09/14/flash-resource-manager-and-flash-8/"/>
    <updated>2005-09-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mikechambers.github.io/2005/09/14/flash-resource-manager-and-flash-8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As many of you have noticed, <a href="http://weblogs.macromedia.com/mesh/archives/2004/07/new_version_of_4.cfm">Flash Resource Manager</a> does not work with Flash 8. This is because the path to the help files is hardcoded (at least for the first load) for Flash MX 2004.</p>

<p>I just played around with the source, and it was pretty easy for me to fix, so once I get the correct version of Visual Studio installed, I am going to try and update it so it will work with both Flash MX 2004 and Flash 8.</p>

<p>In the meantime, if you look in the install directory for the Flash Resource Manager, you should find a config directory with app.config file. This is an XML file that contains all of the settings for the app. You should be able to change the file paths here to get it to work correctly. I haven&#8217;t been able to get get this to work yet, but I wanted to post it here in case anyone wanted to try (post in the comments if you get it working).</p>

<p>UPDATE : Ritesh has confirmed in the comments that you can get it to work with Flash 8 by manually editing the config file.</p>

<p>UPDATE 2: I can&#8217;t get the app to work correct on the WIndows .NET 2.0 beta, so if you are having problems, that might be the issue.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Version of Flash Resource Manager : Adds Support for Flash 7.2]]></title>
    <link href="http://mikechambers.github.io/2004/07/27/new-version-of-flash-resource-manager-adds-support-for-flash-72/"/>
    <updated>2004-07-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mikechambers.github.io/2004/07/27/new-version-of-flash-resource-manager-adds-support-for-flash-72</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have released a new version of my <a href="/mesh/archives/004700.cfm">Flash Resource Manager</a> for Windows. Among other things, this release adds support for <a href="http://www.macromedia.com/software/flash/special/7_2updater/">Flash MX 7.2 (Ellipsis)</a>.</p>

<p>Here is a complete list of changes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Added support for Flash MX 2004 7.2.</li>
<li>Added option to not view help files installed by extensions.</li>
<li>You can now set files as start page. You must enter a valid URI.</li>
<li>Added home page link to go menu.</li>
<li>Latest News link in go menu now goes to latest news, and not home page.</li>
<li>Added version support to application settings. The application will only load settings if the settings were created by the same version of the application.</li>
</ul>


<p>You can download the new version, as well as find out more information <a href="/mesh/archives/004700.cfm">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flash Resource Manager Video Tutorials]]></title>
    <link href="http://mikechambers.github.io/2004/06/17/flash-resource-manager-video-tutorials/"/>
    <updated>2004-06-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mikechambers.github.io/2004/06/17/flash-resource-manager-video-tutorials</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>CommunityMX.com has posted a couple of <a href="http://www.communitymx.com/content/article.cfm?cid=B613C">video tutorials</a> on my <a href="/mesh/archives/004700.cfm">Flash Resource Manager</a> application.</p>

<p>The tutorials show:</p>

<ul>
<li>Installation</li>
<li>Feature overview</li>
<li>Customization</li>
<li>Searching</li>
<li>Creating custom search plugins</li>
</ul>


<p>You can view the tutorials <a href="http://www.communitymx.com/content/article.cfm?cid=B613C">here</a>.</p>

<p>You can find more information about Flash Resource Manager from <a href="/mesh/archives/004700.cfm">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tutorial : Using Flash Resource Manager With Flex Docs]]></title>
    <link href="http://mikechambers.github.io/2004/05/31/tutorial-using-flash-resource-manager-with-flex-docs/"/>
    <updated>2004-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mikechambers.github.io/2004/05/31/tutorial-using-flash-resource-manager-with-flex-docs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Owen Van Dijk has put together a <a href="http://ohwhen.typepad.com/mx_traveller/2004/05/flex_trick_usin.html">step by step tutorial</a> showing how to use the <a href="/mesh/archives/004700.cfm">Flash Resource Manager</a> to read the Flex docs.</p>

<p>This will also work with other HTML based docs, such as ColdFusion.</p>

<p>You can view the entire tutorial <a href="http://ohwhen.typepad.com/mx_traveller/2004/05/flex_trick_usin.html">here</a>.</p>

<p>You can find out more about Flash Resource Manager <a href="/mesh/archives/004700.cfm">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flash Resource Manager Updated / Flex and ColdFusion Support]]></title>
    <link href="http://mikechambers.github.io/2004/04/15/flash-resource-manager-updated-flex-and-coldfusion-support/"/>
    <updated>2004-04-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://mikechambers.github.io/2004/04/15/flash-resource-manager-updated-flex-and-coldfusion-support</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have released a new version of my <a href="/mesh/archives/004700.cfm">Flash Resource Manager application</a>. It includes a bunch of bug fixes, as well as the ability to highlight the search term in search results, and support for Livedoc based HTML docs (Flex, CF and Central have been tested).</p>

<p>Here is the change Log</p>

<ul>
<li>Added ability to add Macromedia HTML based docs (tested with Flex, ColdFusion and Central)</li>
<li>Added Preferences > Help to manage, add and edit which HTML docs are included.</li>
<li>Added Flash HowTo help books to default install.</li>
<li>Added ability to search documents from the help tree context menu (will search for currently selected item).</li>
<li>Added ability to search plugins from the help tree context menu (will search for currently selected item).</li>
<li>Fixed bug where application window would not always have focus when launched.</li>
<li>Added preference to toggle the collapsed state of a node when it is clicked.</li>
<li>Fixed bug where regular expression check box was being ignore in searches (all searches were treated as regular expressions)</li>
<li>Fixed bug where items were added to search filter even if index file was invalid. (Thanks Jason Merrill)</li>
<li>Moved Flash docs to be contained within top level folders / nodes.</li>
<li>Added ability to toggle which top level Flash documents / books are available (View > Preferences > Help).</li>
<li>Improved start up time</li>
<li>Search terms will now be highlighted when viewing search results (this is currently an experimental feature).</li>
<li>Added back / forward browser buttons (I will implement browser features better in future releases)</li>
<li>removed toolbar layout persistence into separate file. This should not be edited by hand.</li>
</ul>


<p>You can find more information, view screenshots, and download the application from <a href="/mesh/archives/004700.cfm">here.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
